Narrator: Jackson, 17
Interviewer: What kind of phone do you have?
Jackson: An iPhone 14.
Interviewer: How old is it?
Jackson: I’m not sure how old it is.
I got it in August, but it was my mom’s old phone.
Interviewer: How often do you change phones?
Jackson: Probably every eighteen months to two years.
Interviewer: What do you use your phone for the most?
Jackson: Texting friends and social media.
Interviewer: How often do you make actual phone calls?
Jackson: Almost never.
Interviewer: What apps do you use a lot?
Jackson: I play a lot of sudoku. I have a sudoku app.
Interviewer: Do you have any unusual apps on your phone?
Jackson: Not really. I think all my apps are pretty normal.
Narrator: Sophie, 40
Interviewer: What kind of phone do you have?
Sophie: It’s a Samsung phone.
Interviewer: How old is it?
Sophie: About a year old, I think.
Interviewer: How often do you change phones?
Sophie: I hate changing phones, so not often.
Unfortunately, my last phone only lasted three years because the battery stopped working.
Interviewer: What do you use your phone for the most?
Sophie: I checked this on my phone, and it said mainly Google.
I research places I'm going to go to, I check my email,
I plan trips using Google maps, I look for reviews for things I'm thinking of buying,
l Iook up meanings of words, I use Google Translate. All on Google.
Interviewer: How often do you make actual phone calls?
Sophie: Once in a blue moon.
Interviewer: What apps do you use a lot?
Sophie: I also checked this, and it said a game called Tile Match!
I was really surprised!
Interviewer: Do you have any unusual apps on your phone?
Sophie: I use an app called FlightTracker to pass the time
while I’m waiting for a flight or waiting to meet someone.
You can follow the path of a plane when it’s coming toward the airport.
I also have an app for jigsaw puzzles.
It's really relaxing to do jigsaw puzzles on your phone. Who knew!
Narrator: Rose, 65
Interviewer: What kind of phone do you have?
Rose: I think it’s an iPhone 13.
An iPhone, anyway.
Interviewer: How old is it?
Rose: I got it about two years ago.
Interviewer: How often do you change phones?
Rose: Every three or four years, usually because the battery isn’t working very well.
Interviewer: What do you use your phone for the most?
Rose: Texting people, checking the news and weather,
sometimes Google Maps for directions, calling taxis,
taking photos, listening to the radio.
Oh, and I sometimes play solitaire.
Interviewer: How often do you make actual phone calls?
Rose: Very rarely.
Only to family or friends when I get bored of writing really long messages.
Interviewer: What apps do you use a lot?
Rose: WhatsApp, Uber, and other taxi apps I have,
the camera, BBC News, BBC Sounds (that’s the radio app).
And banking apps.
Interviewer: Do you have any unusual apps on your phone?
Rose: I have an app for identifying birds by recording their songs
and another to identify flowers by taking a photo.
I sometimes use them when I go for a walk in the country.